

Saad Bin Zafar

Backend/Web Developer



+60 11 10147223



saad@trasso.io saad.zafar.7223@gmail.com



https://github.com/SaadZafar

Profile

A motivated and hardworking individual with a penchant for anything IT or computer related. What he lacks in experience, he makes up with his eagerness to learn new tricks and skills from anyone - regardless of the industry they're working in.

Coding Skills

JavaScript/JQuery	•	•	•	•	
Node.JS	•	•	•	•	
HTML5/CSS		•	•	lacktriangle	
PHP	•	•	•		
C/C++	•	•			
Angular		•			
Vue.js					
Git					

Platforms

AWS

Elasticsearch

Software

Google Cloud	• • • • •	MS Office	• • • • •
Firebase	• • • •	Adobe Photoshop	• • • • •
Freshdesk	• • • • •	VS Code	

WireShark Cisco Packet

Hardware Skills | Soft Skills

Hardware Maintenance	• • • •	Teamwork	• •	• • •
Network Maintenance	• • • •	Multi-tasking	• •	• • •
Cisco CCNA	• • • •	Problem Solving	• •	• • •

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science, 2013-2016 CGPA: 3.33 / 4 Swinburne University of Technology KUCHING, MALAYSIA

A-Levels, St. Patrick's High School 2010-2012 KARACHI, PAKISTAN

Interests











gaming

reading

Extra-Curricular Activities

Head of IT - Swinburne Sarawak Student Council, Kuching, Malaysia	2016
Director - Student Recreation Center @ Swinburne, Kuching, Malaysia	2016
Chief Organizer - DOTA Competition @ SwinCarnival, Kuching, Malaysia	2016
Event Photographer - MOZO (bar & club), Kuching, Malaysia	2015

Projects

UNDERGRAD FINAL YEAR PROJECT

Health Care System

Website (doctors) + Android app (patients)

Website to be used as a portal for doctors to register patients and monitor their progress

App to be used by the patients to upload their medical data (heart rate, blood glucose, etc.) daily, set pill/appointment reminders and view a list of pills and their details

Data from app uploaded to server to be viewed in realtime by the doctors (graph view)

Doctors are able to download the data as spreadsheet for clinical studies

Work Experience

Radica Software Sdn. Bhd. Software Development Intern

AUG 2016 - FEB 2017

Vecta is an online, real-time collaborative, precision diagramming tool for individuals and teams to boost their productivity.

Main Responsibilities:

- ~ Create an authentication system that would allow only users of Vecta to query the ElasticSearch database.
- ~ Designing a permission structure for the Firebase database

- ~ Designing the structure for symbols which serve as pre-designed templates to be used by the users.
- ~Deployment of the web application on Amazon Web Services Elastic Beanstalk
- ~Designing and implementing a new LAN for the office with attached NAS Technologies exposed to:
- ~JavaScript, JQuery, AJAX, PHP, HTML5, CSS, Node.JS, Firebase, ElasticSearch, DynamoDB

Trasso Sdn. Bhd. Application Development Executive -Lead Backend Developer

FEB 2017 - PRESENT

Trasso is a startup company set up in Kuching, Malaysia to boost the e-commerce industry in the state of Sarawak. I was one of the founding members and have been serving as the lead backend developer.

Trasso's flagship product is i-fix, an application that serves as a platform for Repairmen and the Customers to connect. i-fix allows Repairmen to signup and bid on jobs posted by Customers. Job posters can then browse through the bids by repairmen on their job and hire a Repairman of their choosing.

Main Responsibilities:

- ~ Design the complete database structure for i-fix on Google Firebase.
- ~ Create the i-fix Web Application using Angular.
- ~ Create the Trasso and i-fix Application Landing Pages (https://trasso.io & https://i-fix.io)
- ~ Create the API and backend logic for the i-fix mobile apps to interact with the database.

References

Dr. Patrick Then Hang Hui, Associate Dean - Computing, Swinburne University of Technology +60 82 260 682 | pthen@swinburne.edu.my

Mr. Thomas Yip, CEO, Radica Software Sdn. Bhd. +60 52 538 878 | thomas@radicasoftware.com

Mr. Moiz Ullah, iOS Developer, Mindvalley +60 11 268 08974 | moizullahamir94@gmail.com